Guide to the Vice President for Finance and Administration Records, 1819-2017
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series III. 2025 Addition, 1819-2017
  - Property Records, 1819-2017
    - Deeds - Coapman, John S. to John S. Wing, 1866 Mar 30; [1 item, 3 pages] (Folder 36.9)
    - Deeds - Davies, August and May to Vassar College, 1907-1953; [7 items] (Folder 36.10)
    - Deeds - Davies, Thomas L. to Matthew Vassar (and earlier deeds to the same land), 1819-1860; [10 items] (Folder 36.11)
    - Deeds - Dean, Willard L., "memorandum of the title to a lot on College Avenue,", 1890 Sep 17; [1 item] (Folder 36.12)
    - Deeds - Heroy, Helen Chase to Vassar College, 1980 (Folder 36.13)
    - Deeds - Keys, David R., Erskine M., and Jessie J., to Florence V. Keys, 1911 Jul; [2 items] (Folder 36.14)
    - Deeds - Morgan, Caleb to Matthew Vassar (and Reuben Tanner to Caleb Morgan) for the Mill Farm, 1844-1854; [5 items] (Folder 36.15)
    - Deeds - Owsley, Henry F. to Vassar College, 1935 Jul-Aug; [4 items] (Folder 36.16)
    - Deeds - Philips, Francis to Matthew Vassar (and John A. Vanderburgh to Francis Philips), 1853-1860; [5 items] (Folder 36.17)
    - Deeds - Reick, Josephine C. to Vassar College, 1924 Dec 1; [1 item] (Folder 36.18)
    - Deeds - Survey of Collegeview Avenue, [1888?]; [1 item] (Folder 36.19)
    - Deeds - Vanderburgh, John A. to Vassar College, 1870 Dec 1; [2 items] (Folder 36.20)
    - Deeds - Vassar Brothers Hospital to Vassar College for Horton Farm (and earlier deeds to the same land), 1863-1895; [6 items] (Folder 36.21)
    - Deeds - Zuccaro, Carlo to Vassar College (Montana property), 1973-1989; [4 items] (Folder 36.22)
    - Deeds - Notes and plans, undated; [7 items] (Folder 36.23)
    - "Deferred Maintenance Reassessment,", 1992 Apr-May (Folder 40.1)
    - Easements, 1967-1973 (Folder 36.24)
    - Easements - Central Hudson Gas and Electric, 1953-1977 (Folder 36.25)
    - Easements - Sewer easements, 1944-1961 (Folder 36.26)
    - "Facilities Final Exposure - Campus Wide," by the Facilities Resource Management Co., 1986 Dec (Folder 40.2)
    - "Facilities Needs Reassessment,", 1992 Apr 9 (Folder 40.3)
    - Faculty Houses, 1904-1970 (Folder 36.27)
    - Faculty Houses, 1962-1987 (Folder 36.28)
    - Faculty Houses - Appraisal Report, 1972 Nov (Folder 36.29)
    - Faculty Housing, 1957-1961 (Folder 36.30)
    - Faculty Housing - 5 Year Survey, 1979 (Folder 36.31)
    - Faculty Housing - Leases (blank), 1960-1961 (Folder 36.32)
    - Faculty Housing - Rental Analysis Appraisal Report, 1973 (Folder 36.33)
    - "Faculty Housing Property Assessment, Part 1,", 2000 Jan (Folder 40.4)
    - Faculty Housing Study, 1998 Apr (Folder 36.34)
    - Landscape Master Plan - Final report, 1988 Sep 1 (Folder 40.5)
    - Leases - Boardman property, 1901 Mar 9 (Folder 36.35)
    - Parking Study, 2002 (Folder 40.6)
    - "Preliminary Landscape Survey,", 1984 Sep (Folder 40.7)
    - "Preliminary Traffic Plan,", 1972 Aug (Folder 40.8)
    - Properties - "Administration Building,", 1954 (Folder 36.36)
    - Properties - All College Dining Center (ACDC), 1966-1972 (Folder 36.37)
    - Properties - All College Dining Center (ACDC), 1973 (Folder 36.38)
    - Properties - All College Dining Center (ACDC), 1974-1977 (Folder 36.39)
    - Properties - Alumnae House, 1922-1925 (Folder 36.40)
    - Properties - Alumnae House, 1939-1974 (Folder 36.41)
    - Properties - Avery Hall, 1915-1939 (Folder 36.42)
    - Properties - Baldwin House, 1939-1961 (Folder 36.43)
    - Properties - Bartow property, 1978-1981 (Folder 36.44)
    - Properties - Blodgett Hall, 1948, 1999 (Folder 36.45)
    - Properties - Boat House/Waterfront property (Dutton Property), 1988-1992 (Folder 36.46)
    - Properties - Boat House/Waterfront property, 1993 (Folders 36.47-36.48)
    - Properties - Boat House/Waterfront property, 1994 (Folder 36.49)
    - Properties - Boat House/Waterfront property, 1995 (Folders 37.1-37.2)
    - Properties - Boat House/Waterfront property, 1996 (Folder 37.3)
    - Properties - Boat House/Waterfront property, 1997-2000 (Folder 37.4)
    - Properties - Boat House/Waterfront property, 2002-2004 (Folder 37.5)
    - Properties - Boat House, Albany Miron Lumber Corporation, 1995 (Folder 37.6)
    - Properties - Boat House, Albany Miron Lumber Corporation, 1995-1996 (Folder 37.7)
    - Properties - Boat House, City of Poughkeepsie land swap, 1997 (Folder 37.8)
    - Properties - Boat House, Deed, 1995 Sep 11 (Folder 37.9)
    - Properties - Boat House, Hudson River Rowing Association, 1999-2005 (Folder 37.10)
    - Properties - Boat House, "Limited Phase II Subsurface Investigation," draft, 1995 Jan (Folder 37.11)
    - Properties - Boat House, "Limited Phase II Subsurface Investigation,", 1995 Mar (Folder 37.12)
    - Properties - Boat House, New D. Corp contract of sale, 1995 Mar 23 (Folder 37.13)
    - Properties - Boat House, New D. Corp closing statement, 1995 Sep 11 (Folder 37.14)
    - Properties - Boat House, "Preliminary Real Property Appraisal,", 1993 Apr 8 (Folder 37.15)
    - Properties - Boat House, plans, 1995, undated (Folder 37.16)
    - Properties - Boat House, requisitions, 1993-1996 (Folder 37.17)
    - Properties - 131 Boardman Rd (IBM property), 1997 (Folder 37.18)
    - Properties - 703 Boardman Rd (Library Annex), 2002-2006 (Folder 37.19)
    - Properties - 703 Boardman Rd (Library Annex), acquisition from IBM, 1993-1994 (Folder 37.20)
    - Properties - Boiler House A, 1911-1959 (Folder 38.1)
    - Properties - Chapel, 1899-1966 (Folder 38.2)
    - Properties - Chicago Hall, 1954-1959 (Folder 38.3)
    - Properties - Coal Pockets (Cottage St), 1897-1968 (Folder 38.4)
    - Properties - 141 College Ave (Gow House), 1901-1950 (Folder 38.5)
    - Properties - 147 College Ave (Lyman Cottage), 1924-1945 (Folder 38.6)
    - Properties - 149 College Ave (Keys House), 1948-1952 (Folder 38.7)
    - Properties - 168A College Ave, 1957-1987 (Folder 38.8)
    - Properties - College Center, 1968-1975 (Folder 38.9)
    - Properties - 37 Collegeview Ave, 1974-1998 (Folder 38.10)
    - Properties - 43 Collegeview Ave (Matzig House), 1969 (Folder 38.11)
    - Properties - 51 Collegeview Ave (Bartram House), 1973-1998 (Folder 38.12)
    - Properties - Cushing House, 1927-1974 (Folder 38.13)
    - Properties - Davison House, 1901-1959 (Folder 38.14)
    - Properties - Dean's House, 1931 (Folder 38.15)
    - Properties - Ely Hall (Aula), 1889-1941 (Folder 38.16)
    - Properties - Ferry House, 1949-1961 (Folder 38.17)
    - Properties - Golf Course, 1951-1988 (Folder 38.18)
    - Properties - Golf Course, 1990-2002 (Folder 38.19)
    - Properties - Golf Course, 2003 (Folder 38.20)
    - Properties - Golf Course, 2004 (Folder 38.21)
    - Properties - Golf Course, 2005-2010 (Folder 38.22)
    - Properties - 334 Hooker Ave (Murphy House), 1967-1972 (Folder 38.23)
    - Properties - The Inn at Vassar, 2014-2017 (Folder 38.24)
    - Properties - Jewett House, 1906 (Folder 38.25)
    - Properties - Josselyn House, 1910-1911, 1949 (Folder 38.26)
    - Properties - Kautz Admission House (Goodfellowship House), 1907-1996 (Folder 38.27)
    - Properties - Kendrick House (Myra H. Avery bequest), 1923-1960 (Folder 38.28)
    - Properties - Kenyon Hall, 1929-1971 (Folder 38.29)
    - Properties - Lathrop House, 1900 (Folder 38.30)
    - Properties - Library, Thompson Memorial, 1949-1975 (Folder 38.31)
    - Properties - Library, Lockwood Addition, 1975-1976 (Folder 38.32)
    - Properties - Main Building, 1907-1986 (Folder 38.33)
    - Properties - Metcalf House, 1915-1945 (Folder 38.34)
    - Properties - New England Building, 1901-1912 (Folder 38.35)
    - Properties - 2500 New Hackensack Rd, Poughkeepsie Day School (formerly 39 New Hackensack Rd), 1962-1971 (Folder 38.36)
    - Properties - 2500 New Hackensack Rd, Poughkeepsie Day School (formerly 39 New Hackensack Rd), 1975-2000 (Folder 38.37)
    - Properties - Noyes Hall, 1959-1969 (Folder 38.38)
    - Properties - Noyes Hall, 1970-1975 (Folder 38.39)
    - Properties - Noyes Hall, Building Specifications, 1957 Jun 26 (Folder 38.40)
    - Properties - Observatory, Maria Mitchell, 1989-1991 (Folder 39.1)
    - Properties - Olmsted Hall, 1966-1971 (Folder 39.2)
    - Properties - Olmsted Hall, 1972 (Folder 39.3)
    - Properties - Olmsted Hall, 1973 (Folder 39.4)
    - Properties - Olmsted Hall, 1974, 1981 (Folder 39.5)
    - Properties - 3 Orchard Lane, 1950-1954 (Folder 39.6)
    - Properties - Palmer House (Wing Farm), 1923-1968 (Folder 39.7)
    - Properties - Power House Theater, 1972-1973 (Folder 39.8)
    - Properties - Pratt House, 1915-1969 (Folder 39.9)
    - Properties - President's House, 1932, 1965 (Folder 39.10)
    - Properties - 69 Raymond Ave (formerly 104 Raymond Ave; Tonks property), 1931-1997 (Folder 39.11)
    - Properties - 77 Raymond Ave (formerly 112 Raymond Ave; Hill House), 1904-1949 (Folder 39.12)
    - Properties - 85 Raymond Ave (formerly 120 Raymond Ave; Cottage B), 1949 (Folder 39.13)
    - Properties - Raymond House, 1897 (Folder 39.14)
    - Properties - Rockefeller Hall, 1896-1897 (Folder 39.15)
    - Properties - Rombout House, 1901-1913 (Folder 39.16)
    - Properties - Rombout House, 1915 (Folder 39.17)
    - Properties - Rombout House, 1935-1947 (Folder 39.18)
    - Properties - Sanders Chemistry, 1907-1987 (Folder 39.19)
    - Properties - Sanders Physics, 1921 - circa 1933 (Folder 39.20)
    - Properties - Service Building, 1939 (Folder 39.21)
    - Properties - Smithfield Estates Farm Property, 1936, 1952 (Folder 39.22)
    - Properties - Strong House, 1939 (Folder 39.23)
    - Properties - Student's Building, 1918-1969 (Folder 39.24)
    - Properties - Swift Hall, 1899-1900 (Folder 39.25)
    - Properties - Terrace Apartments, 1971-1973 (Folder 39.26)
    - Properties - Town Houses, 1969-1976 (Folder 39.27)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, 1953-1961 (Folder 39.28)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, 1972-1993 (Folder 39.29)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, 1995-2017 (Folder 39.30)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, Boots and Saddle Club of Poughkeepsie, 1959-1962 (Folder 39.31)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, composting project, 1988-1999 (Folder 39.32)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, Environmental Science Laboratory and Nature Center, 1993-1994 (Folder 39.33)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, Field Station, 1983-1995 (Folder 39.34)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, "Report on the History and Current Use of the Vassar Farm,", 2006 (Folder 39.35)
    - Properties - Vassar Farm, silo replacement, 1995 (Folder 39.36)
    - Properties - 6 West Winding Rd (Paschal House), 1980-1982 (Folder 39.37)
    - Properties - 18 Wilbur Blvd (Anita Zorzoli property), 1992-1998 (Folder 39.38)
    - Properties - Wimpfheimer Nursery School, 2004-2011 (Folder 39.39)
    - Properties - 218 Winnikee Ave (Sportsmens Cricket Club, former Black Studies Urban Center), 1981-1982 (Folder 39.40)
    - Property Condition Survey, 1997 Oct (Folder 40.9)
    - Property Condition Survey of Vassar College, 1997 Oct; [VHS tape] (Folder 40.10)
    - "Refurbishing Survey,", 1979 Jan (Folder 40.11)
    - Report on the Development of a Project List for Tax-Exempt Bond Financing, 1989 (Folder 40.12)
    - Residential Facilities Master Plan, 2000 May (Folders 40.13-40.14)
    - Residential Facilities Master Plan - Addendum, 2000 Aug (Folder 40.15)
    - Residential Properties - Appraisal Reports, Vol. 1, 1993 (Folder 40.16)
    - Residential Properties - Appraisal Reports, Vol. 2, 1993 (Folder 40.17)
    - Site Evaluations: Student Housing, 1990 May 4 (Folder 40.18)
    - Surveys and audits (?), 1978-1980 (Folder 39.41)
    - Tax certificates, 1937-1992 (Folder 39.42)
    - Utilities - Gas, 1907 (Folder 39.43)
    - Utilities - Sewer, Arlington, 1956-1970 (Folder 39.44)
    - Utilities - Sewer and Sewer Pump House, 1894-1946 (Folder 39.45)
    - Utilities - Water supply, City of Poughkeepsie, 1912-1970 (Folder 39.46)
    - Utilities and Grounds, 1908, 1914 (Folder 39.47)
    - Utility Systems Master Plan, 1996 Aug (Folder 40.19)
    - "Utility Systems Master Plan" by the Facilities Resource Management Co., 1996 Apr 23 (Folder 40.20)
    - "Utility Master Plan - Presentation,", 1996 Apr 23 (Folder 40.21)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study, 1972-1976 (Folder 41.1)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study, 1974-1975 (Folder 41.2)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study, 1974-1976 (Folder 41.3)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study, 1975-1977 (Folder 41.4)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study - Phase I Report, 1974 Dec (Folder 41.5)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study - Phase II Report, 1975 Feb (Folder 41.6)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study - Phase III Report, 1975 Oct (Folder 41.7)
    - Vassar Farm Study - Report of the Campus Master Planning Committee, undated (Folder 41.8)
    - Vassar Farm Proposal - National Audubon Society, 1974 Sep (Folder 41.9)
    - Vassar Farm Concept Plan Study - Final Report by Sasaki Associates, 1976 (Folder 41.10)
    - Wheelchair Accessibility Survey, 1992 (Folder 41.11)
  - Committee Records, 1968-2015
    - Arlington/Juliet Committee Minutes, 2004-2008 (Folder 41.12)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Combined minutes and correspondence, 1968 Sep - 1969 Dec (Folder 41.13)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Combined minutes and correspondence, 1970 Jan-Dec (Folder 41.14)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Combined minutes and correspondence, 1971 Jan-1973 May (Folder 41.15)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Combined minutes and correspondence, 1973 Jun - 1975 Apr (Folder 41.16)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Combined minutes and correspondence, 1975 May - 1979 Feb (Folder 41.17)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1968 Sep - 1970 Feb (Folder 41.18)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1970 Feb - 1972 Feb (Folder 41.19)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1972 Mar - 1975 Dec (Folder 41.20)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1976 Jan - 1979 Dec (Folder 41.21)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1980 Feb - 1984 Dec (Folder 42.1)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1985 May - 1990 Dec (Folder 42.2)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1991 Feb - 1997 Dec (Folder 42.3)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 1998 Jan - 2003 Feb (Folder 42.4)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Minutes, 2003 Apr - 2008 Feb (Folder 42.5)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Reports from departments, 1968-1970 (Folders 42.6-42.9)
    - Campus Master Planning Committee - Report, 1969 May (Folder 42.10)
    - Investments and Finance Committee - Reports, 1986-1999 (Folders 45.6-45.10)
    - Priorities and Planning Committee, 1997-2001 (Folder 42.11)
    - Priorities and Planning Committee, 2002-2007 Apr (Folder 42.12)
    - Priorities and Planning Committee, 2003-2004 (Folder 42.13)
    - Priorities and Planning Committee, 2014-2015 (Folder 42.14)
  - Bond Records, 1990-2017
    - Bonds - 1990 Series (Folders 42.15-42.16)
    - Bonds - 1990 Series, draft resolution (Folder 42.17)
    - Bonds - 1995 Series (Folders 42.18-42.19)
    - Bonds - 1995 Series, 1995-1996 (Folder 42.20)
    - Bonds - 1995 Series, refinancing, 1996 (Folder 42.21)
    - Bonds - 2001 Series, 1998-2012; [3 folders] (Box 43)
    - Bonds - 2007 Series, 2004-2017; [8 folders] (Box 43)
    - Bonds - 2010 Series, 2007-2010; [9 folders] (Box 43)
    - Bonds - 2013 Series, [5 folders] (Box 43)
    - Bonds - 2013 Series (Folders 44.1-44.2)
    - Bonds - Compliance documents, 2007-2015 (Folder 44.3)
    - Bonds - Miscellaneous supporting documents, 2007-2012 (Folders 44.4-44.5)
  - Middle States Association Self-Study Records, 1978-2009
    - "Overview Committee of the Vassar Self-Study,", 1978 (Folder 44.14)
    - Middle States File, 1989-1999 (Folder 44.6)
    - Middle States Report - Correspondence, 1989 (Folder 44.7)
    - Self-Study Report, 1989 (Folders 44.8-44.9)
    - Middle States, 1994 (Folder 44.10)
    - Self-Study Report, draft, 1998 Apr (Folder 44.11)
    - Subcommittee on Finances and Facilities of the Self-Study Steering Committee for the Middle States Association Accreditation, 1999 (Folder 44.12)
    - Self-Study, 2009 (Folder 44.13)
  - Miscellaneous Records, 1968-2016
    - Administrative Handbook, 1990 Sep (Folder 44.15)
    - "Cambridge Report" on long-range financial equilibrium, 1982 May 15 (Folder 44.16)
    - Capital Planning, 2001-2002 (Folders 44.17-44.18)
    - "The Club - Founded 1887,", undated (Folder 44.19)
    - "College Properties LLC - Articles of Organization,", 1999 Oct (Folder 44.20)
    - Contracts - Aramark Education, 2005-2006 (Folder 44.21)
    - Contracts - Mac Gray Corporation, 2003 (Folder 44.22)
    - Financial Landscape Report, 2016 Feb (Folder 44.23)
    - "The Financial Picture of Vassar College,", 1973 Nov 7 (Folder 44.24)
    - "The Governance of Vassar College,", circa 2010 (Folder 44.25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-2003 (Folder 44.26)
    - Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1992 Oct - 2010 May (Folders 45.1-45.3)
    - Valuation of Private Equity Investments, 2006 (Folder 45.4)
    - Vassar-Yale Study Group, Budget Report, 1968 Jan 31 (Folder 45.5)
  - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 1980-2010
    - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 1980-1982; [2 folders] (Box 46)
    - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 1983-1985; [2 folders] (Box 46)
    - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 1986-2003; [17 folders] (Box 46)
    - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 2003-2004; [3 folders] (Box 46)
    - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 2004-2005; [2 folders] (Box 46)
    - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 2005-2007; [2 folders] (Box 46)
    - Tax Forms 990 and 990T, 2009-2010 (Box 46)